Dhrubo Talukder

New York, New York | 646-875-2316 | dhrubo.dh@gmail.com

Github: Dhrubot | https://dhrubot.github.io | personal portfolio/website: https://dhrubot.com

Full Stack Web Developer | Software Engineer

Full stack web developer experienced in Ruby and JavaScript frameworks and focused on creating applications with strong user interface (UI), user experience (UX), and responsive design. Solutions-driven, highly technical professional who perceives situations differently and develops ideas and approaches to resolve unique problems by engaging with invested customers. Engineer who recognizes patterns, develops solutions, and writes clean code to bring ideas to life.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, SQL, Sqlite3, MySQL, PostgreSQL, AWS, Sinatra, JavaScript, React, Redux, Bootstrap, Material-ui, HTML, CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Circle - https://github.com/Dhrubot/circle-frontend | Demo - https://youtu.be/R-lwk4f sGI

Social media platform that opens a window for users to share and cherish daily life and special moments with each other.

- Utilized Bcrypt, Sessions, and Cookies to store and secure encrypted user information server-side.
- Achieved full CRUD functionality through Rails API for effective backend.
- Implemented user interface, employing React and Redux frontend.
- Focused on and developed responsive design across multiple platforms using Bootstrap.

Space Shooter - https://github.com/Dhrubot/space-shooter-frontend | Demo - https://youtu.be/vws3uSpW-il

Shooting game where users can explore their missions and compete for the high score.

- Used JavaScript to manipulate DOM for interactive user experience.
- Developed Rails API for backend with endpoints for both user and game data.
- Employed custom CSS for strong styling and user interface.

PalmKings - https://github.com/Dhrubot/palmkings | Demo-https://youtu.be/SdoRSKEw-lo

Marketplace for buying and selling cell phones.

- Stored, encrypted, and secured user information server-side, utilizing Bcrypt, Sessions, and Cookies.
- Launched program for production using PostgreSQL and AWS S3 for persisting and returning data faster.
- Implemented user interface features employing Ruby on Rails, allowing for a more interactive user experience.
- Utilized Bootstrap for responsive design across multiple platforms.

EXPERIENCE

UberNew York, NYRideshare Driver01/2015 - 11/2019

- Averaged 13 trips per day, taking customers to respective destinations as quickly as possible around New York City, as well as parts of New York State, New Jersey, and Connecticut.
- Provided transportation services in a courteous and professional manner, consistently maintaining a 4.95/5.0 rating.
- Learned about and drove shortest routes to destinations city-wide, getting passengers to destinations on time.

Apparel Production Inc.

New York, NY
1T Administrator
03/2016 - 04/2017

- Updated company website and social media pages to show new products and related data, often using Adobe Photoshop; collaborated with server provider to resolve backend issues.
- Avoided losses to the company by regularly managing databases with 45 clients and 15 suppliers, updating files and product information and troubleshooting issues within one day on average.
- Supported and resolved issues for 20 workstations, troubleshooting hardware and software problems, reaching out
 to product experts for any changes or updates, and communicating on an ongoing basis with 15+ employees.

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Borough of Manhattan Community College

Associate in Applied Science; Major: Computer Network Technology

01/2014 - 01/2021 New York, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

04/2020 - 09/2020

New York, NY

Technical Institute of America

Flatiron School

New York, NY

Cisco Network Associate; Routing and Switching

09/2017 - 12/2017